Vasileios Nikolopoulos

Lead Developer | Certified Scrum Maser | PhD Candidate

Born 1991 in Athens, GR



About me

Hi, my name is Vasileios Nikolopoulos. I'm a Software engineer, with Java expertise, while also being a Professional Scrum Master, and leading a small group of people as CEO of Jar (jar.gr)

Additionally I am a PhD candidate at Harokopio University of Athens, on Context-Aware IoT and autonomous Fog/Edge nodes. Keen on researching new technologies and innovating

Skills

Team Leading

Mentoring

Stakeholder Management

Customer Relations

Requirements Capturing

Project Risk Management

Distributed Systems

RESTful communications

Agile/Scrum Methodologies

Contact



Oude Huys 16



nikolopoulosbasil@gmail.com



L +31 0615067138



https://nikolopoulosbasil.com



Experience

Software Engineer

Forescout Technologies Inc.

July 2018 - Present

Backend development using a Java and pSql stack. Heavy emphasis on RESTful communications. Technically led three products (Risk Framework, ECC, IT/OT integration) which launched successfully and ended up as the selling points for large deals. Scrum Master for a senior team. Direct discussions with stakeholders for negotiation of development effort and updates on project status. Direct discussions with customers for troubleshooting.

Founder | CEO | Project Manager

Jar

July 2018 - Present

Outsourcing of development effort by outsourcing Scrum ready teams.

Research Associate/Software Engineer

Harokopio University of Athens

February 2015 - Present

Participating in European Research Projects (i.e. Artemis EMC2) as a Software Engineer and Researcher. Proof of Concepts for our research was implemented in Java.

Software Engineer L2

Openbet

November 2016 - September 2017

Software engineer using Java and TCL for backend development of client ordered changes on betting software.

CMS/Android Programmer

Express Publishing

September 2013 - February 2015

Part of the Multimedia team, working on creating a custom builder to transform information from a data entry department to interactive Mobile Applications. Also developed custom tools for the business in Java.

Software Engineer

Freelancer

June 2012 - July 2018

Implementing customer ordered projects, using primarily Java and JS solutions, but also Android Stack, Unity Game engine, and Embedded Systems (Arduino/Raspberry Pis).



Education

Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) (Candidate)

April 2015 - Present | Harokopio University of Athens

Context-aware IoT, An Autonomic Approach targeting Multi-critical **Applications**

Master of Science

September 2013 - February 2015 | Harokopio University of Athens Computational and Internet, Technologies and Applications

Bachelor of Science

September 2009 - September 2013 | Harokopio University of Athens Bachelor's degree on Informatics and Telematics